&gt;&gt; Good morning
&gt;&gt; 早上好
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm Chris Dreessen.
我是 Chris Dreesen
This is Touch Bar Fundamentals.
这里是“Touch Bar Fundamentals（Touch Bar 基础）”
If you have no idea whatsoever
如果你还不知道
what Touch Bar is, I'm not sure
什么是 Touch Bar  那我真的不确定你为什么
how you got here, but I'm glad
会在这儿出现 但是我对你的到来
you're here.
感到非常开心
Likely most of us are a bit more
或许我们中的绝大多数人都
familiar with Touch Bar, but we
对 Touch Bar 有所了解  但是
may not have had a chance to
可能还没有机会去
actually play with it.
真正使用它
So, let me orient you to it.
所以 让我来为大家介绍一下
So, we have here a picture of a
现在我们这里有一张 MacBook Pro
MacBook Pro and in place of the
的图片 在你们熟悉的
F keys you might be used to, we
功能键的位置 我们有一个
have this thing we call Touch
叫做 Touch Bar 的
Bar.
东西
And this is an interactive input
这是一个交互式输入
and display device.
和显示的设备
And let me familiarize you with
让我带领大家来
these parts.
熟悉它
On the left, we have the escape
在触摸条左边有我们每个人
key, which should be pretty
都非常熟悉的
familiar to everyone.
Escape 键
And on the right, we have this
在右边
thing called the control script.
有一个叫做 Control Strip 的东西
And you can go ahead and
如果你愿意
disclose the control strip if
你可以展开
you want.
Control Strip
And you'll have basically the
这样 你将会得到和
old media functions the F keys
以前的功能键一样的
offer.
功能
And you can use this the same
然后你可以和原来一样
way you always have, button
把它们当成按钮来
presses.
使用
You don't have to disclose it
不过 你其实不必
thought.
展开它
You can actually just go ahead
你可以直接
and use it in its collapsed
使用它的折叠
form.
形式
And when it's its collapsed form
当它处于折叠形式的时候
it has some neat functions too.
它同样有很多巧妙的功能
We can just do like a glancing
我们可以通过直接在
swipe over the volume button and
音量键上随意滑动
adjust the volume directly.
来调整声音大小
So, there's a lot of
这里有很多
conveniences here for adjusting
便捷的方式来调整
certain system functions.
特定的系统功能
But, that's not really the most
但是 这还不是 Touch Bar 最
interesting parts of Touch Bar,
有趣的部分
the most interesting parts are
最有趣的部分在
between the escape key and the
Escape 键和 Control Strip 键
control strip.
之间
And that's where your
这里是你的
application content is going to
应用程序内容所处的
go.
位置
And so, let me show you what
让我来向你们展示
some of our system applications
我们的系统应用
have done with this.
在这里的
So, here we have photos.
这里是“照片”应用
And this is just browsing the
我们正在浏览
photos library.
照片库
And we can actually go ahead and
我们可以
scrub through our photo library
在这里滑动浏览
here.
照片库
It's just like in iOS with
这就像在 iOS 里可以直接
direct input with our finger, so
用我们的手指输入一样
we plop our finger down on the
我们将手指放在
Touch Bar and it's just tracking
Touch Bar 上然后它就会追踪我们的
it.
指尖
We also have momentum swipes
如果我们希望能快速地进行浏览
there if we want to browse
我们可通过快速滑动
through it quickly.
来实现
If you go to edit a photo, this
如果你想编辑图片 这里
is the photos crop and rotate
是图片剪裁和旋转
tool.
工具
And they have this rotation
在 Touch Bar 中间有一个
thing in the middle of the Touch
可以直接跟踪
Bar and it tracks your finger
你的手指的旋转控件
directly, which is pretty fun,
它很有趣 因为
because it's sort of like
这有点像直接在
actually rotating a picture on a
桌上用手指旋转
table.
图片
Finally, photos also exposes
最后 图片还可以使用
filters.
滤镜
So, we can scrub and swipe
我们可以在滤镜之间
through our filters here.
滑动
And this is an interesting use
这是 Touch Bar 的一个有趣的
of Touch Bar, because normally
使用方式 因为通常我们使用
if we were using a mouse or a
鼠标或者触控板时
track pad, we'd go ahead and
我们会
look at our photo and then look
先看照片 然后
at the filters section and move
看滤镜部分
the mouse or track pad to that,
再用鼠标和触控板
select the next filter.
选择下一个滤镜
And with Touch Bar we can
使用 Touch Bar 我们可以
actually keep our eyes on the
只将视线放在猫
cat.
上
Here's QuickTime Player.
这里是一个 QuickTime 播放器
QuickTime Player has a scrubber
它在 Touch Bar 上有一个
control directly in the touch
滑动控制器
bar, so we can move a movie back
使我们能对一部电影快进或快退
and forth, it's pretty neat.
简单利落
And they've also gone ahead and
他们还提供
exposed a similar control for
一个类似的剪辑功能控件
trimming, so we can adjust the
使我们能调整
beginning and end of a movie
我们所拍摄的电影的
that we've recorded.
开头和结尾
Something I'd like to point out
关于 QuickTime 播放器
about QuickTime Player here, is
我想指出的是
that QuickTime Player didn't
QuickTime 播放器没有
write any code to do this, this
对此功能编写任何程序 此功能
is all inside of AVKit and
是包括在 AVKit 和 AVplayer 视图
AVPlayer view.
中
So, if you're already using
如果你已经在使用
AVKit, you've probably got this
AVKit 那么恭喜你 你可能已经
functionality for free,
自动获得了这项
congratulations.
功能
Let's look at text edit for a
现在让我们来看看文本
moment.
编辑
So, everyone's familiar with
在座各位应该很熟悉
QuickType on iOS.
iOS 上的 QuickType 了
And We've gone ahead and brought
我们已经将 QuickType
QuickType over to Touch Bar on
放置在了 macOS 的 Touch Bar 上
macOS, and as everyone know
众所周知
QuickType is a great short
QuickType 是一个非常好的短篇小说
fiction writing tool.
写作工具
So, if we go ahead and write a
如果我们在这里写一个小故事
short story here, 'the fact is
其实这不是
he has to;' this is not the best
我看过的最好的
short fiction I've read.
短篇小说
But that's okay, because Touch
但是没关系 因为
Bar gives us a way of spicing
Touch Bar 能为我们提供一个让其增色
that up.
的方法
We also have the emoji picker.
我们还有表情符号选择条
And, let's go ahead and spice it
我们来让它变得有趣
up a bit.
一点
We can browse our emoji here and
我们可以在这里浏览表情符号
say I laughed until I cried, I
比如 我笑了 我哭了
was turned into a frog, and I'm
我变成了一只青蛙 然后我很开心
happy I'm no longer a frog.
因为我不再是一只青蛙了
So, we've added some nice human
我为我们的故事加上了一些非常好的人物情感
emotion and drama to our story,
和喜剧效果
all thanks to Touch Bar.
而这都要感谢 Touch Bar
TextEdit of course, is a text
显而易见文本编辑是一款
editing tool also, so we can
文本编辑工具
collapse the QuickType options
我们可以将 QuickType 的选项折叠起来
here and bring up text
然后调出文本
formatting controls.
排版控件
And maybe the most useful thing
可能最有用的事情就是
is to make it bold, or italic,
让它加粗或者变成斜体
or add some color to it and pink
或者加上颜色
feels right for the story where
粉色感觉很适合故事中
I'm turned into a frog, and not
我变成了青蛙然后不再是青蛙的
a frog again.
部分
Anyway, let's never speak of
不论如何 让我们别再说起
that.
这个了
Something else I want to point
关于我给大家展示的
out about all these examples
这些例子 我还想指出的是
I've show you is that they're
它们都是
customizable.
可以自定义的
We have a customization panel
我们有一个 Touch Bar 的
for Touch Bar.
自定义面板
And you can rearrange items in
你可以在这上面重新编排
it.
控件
You can add items from the
你可以从屏幕上的自定义面板中
customization panel on the
添加控件
screen or remove them from the
也可以将控件从 Touch Bar 中
Touch Bar.
移除
And this is important, because
这很重要
every user's workflow is a
因为每个用户的使用习惯
little bit different.
是不一样的
Some are doing different things
有些人喜欢用
with your application, and
应用做不同的事
others just prefer to use the
有些人则喜欢用其他方式
computer in a different way.
使用电脑
And by enabling customization,
通过实现自定义
you can give users the exact
你可以给用户
experience they want.
他们想要的体验
And I'll teach you how to do
接下来我将教大家
that programmatically in just a
如何通过编程实现这个
little bit.
功能
Let's cover some of the
我们先来讲讲
technical details and some of
这个功能的技术细节
the implications that come with
和这些细节的
that.
含义
So, the Touch Bar is the
Touch Bar 是一个
beautiful P3 retina display.
很绚丽的 P3 Retina 显示器
It has a nice P3 color gamut,
他有很棒的 P3 色域
great blacks, wonderful
迷人的黑色 让显示内容
contrast.
对比鲜明
And that means that our assets
这也意味着
we include in our applications
我们在应用里包含的的素材
don't have to cover as much as
不需要像主屏幕上
what we do on the main screen.
那么多
Additionally, it's a true multi
不仅如此 这还是一个多点触控的设备
touch device, which means we can
这意味着我们能跟踪到
actually track multiple fingers.
多个手指
And that affords us some new
这也为我们能制作的控件
options for what sort of
提供了一些
controls we might make.
新的选择
You're going to hear this a lot
说起 Touch Bar
about Touch Bar, that it's
你经常听到词的将是
context sensitive.
上下文敏感
And that's very neat in terms of
使用户能在合适的应用中
enabling the user to work with
使用功能的
functions in the application
其实很简单
that are appropriate, but it has
但是它具有
implications for event handling,
处理事件的意义
because the context in the
因为我们的用户在使用 Touch Bar 时
application might change, which
应用中的上下文
the user is using the Touch Bar,
可能会发生变化
and our controls need to react
而我们的控件需要对变化
to that.
进行应对
And finally, we actually go
最后 我们
ahead and take some care to
需要将 Touch Bar上的
match the key taps and glyphs on
按钮 符号
the Touch Bar to those on the
与物理键盘
physical keyboard, and we do
进行对应
that by watching the ambient
并且我们通过检测
brightness, and knowing whether
环境的亮度来判断
or not the keyboard backlight is
键盘的背灯是否应该
on.
亮起
But this has implications for
这将影响我们如何
how we might draw custom
绘制自定义
controls.
控件
And we're not going to go into
但是在本次会议里
detail on any of those
我们不会讲到
implications in this session,
相关内容
but we do have a session later
在今天下午的会议上
this afternoon that will cover
将会讲到所有这些
all these topics.
话题
So, I'm assuming that once
我想 只要你听到了这里
you're done here, maybe even
甚至可能在这之前 你就已经
before that, you're going to be
想要把
really jazzed to add Touch Bar
Touch Bar 支持加入到
support to your application if
你的应用中去了
you haven't already.
如果你还没有的话
But when you're coming up with
不过 当你设计你的 UI 时
your UI's there's a few things
有几点是应该
to keep in mind.
记住的
And the first of them, the prime
首先
directive of Touch Bar is that
Touch Bar 的第一指导原则是
the Touch Bar is an input
它是一个输入
device.
设备
It's meant to be interacted with
这意味着它应该能
by the user.
与用户互动
It's not supposed to be
它不应该被当成显示器
displaying things.
来使用
So, no status indicators or
所以 不要加入状态指示器
stock tickers.
或者股票 K 线图
The next thing we should keep in
另外一件需要记住的事是
mind when making our Touch Bar
在制作 Touch Bar UI 时
UI's is that we don't want to
我们不希望将应用中
put functionality in the Touch
别的地方
Bar that doesn't exist anywhere
都没有的功能
else in the application.
加到 Touch Bar 里
It's great to have null and fun
Touch Bar UI 可以有趣 可以存在空白
Touch Bar UI's, but it shouldn't
这些都很好
be the only way of accessing
但这不应该成为访问功能
functionality.
的唯一途径
And there's a good reason for a
这是有原因的
lot of that, and that's that not
因为并非所有
every user has a Touch Bar, so
用户都有 Touch Bar
if you only put something in the
如果你加入了只在
Touch Bar, you're going to be
Touch Bar 上可以使用的功能
losing out on functionality for
那么很多用户都会失去使用这个功能
a lot of users.
的机会
And finally, this is almost a
最后 这几乎可以说是 Touch Bar
side effect of saying the Touch
作为输入设备的
Bar is an input device.
一个副作用
While we want creative beautiful
当我们想要在 Touch Bar 上创造
UI's in the Touch Bar, they
漂亮的 UI 时
shouldn't be taking center
他们不应该喧宾
stage.
夺主
The content the user's working
用户在主屏幕上的工作内容
with on the main screen should
应该永远都是
always be their focus.
他们的焦点
So, the Touch Bar shouldn't be
Touch Bar 不应该使人
distracting.
分心
With that out of the way, we're
说完了这些 我们
going to go ahead and cover the
将要讲到
core classes that let you use
能让你在应用中使用
the Touch Bar in your
Touch Bar 的核心
application.
类
We're going to cover how the
我们将讲到响应器
responder change is integrated
将如何变化 以配合发现
with these for discovering what
应该显示何种
context sensitive functionality
上下文敏感
to display.
功能
And then, we're going to go
然后 我们将
ahead and take a deep dive on
深入探讨
one of those core classes and
其中一门核心类
show you most of what it can do.
并向大家展示它能做什么
So, let's start with the
让我们从类
classes.
开始
The first class is of course
第一节课当然是关于
NSTouchBarItem.
NSTouchBarItem 的
And that plays with NSTouchBar
与它相配合的还有 NSTouchBar
and NSResponder.
和 NSResponder
And let's just take a closer
让我们详细了解
look.
一下
This is a mockup of the mail
这是我做的一个
Touch Bar I've made.
“邮件”应用 Touch Bar 的实体模型
And everything I'm highlighting
所有我标记高亮的部分
here, is an NS view, or NS
要么是一个 NSView 要么是
control, or NS button.
NSControl 要么就是 NSButton
They're all things you're very
这都是大家很熟悉的
familiar with because Touch Bar
因为 Touch Bar 使用的也是
is reusing the existing view
我们已经在
functionality we've been using
我们的 Cocoa App 中
in our Cocoa apps for very long
用过很久的
time.
视图功能
There's a few things though that
有一些事是 Touch Bar 能做到
Touch Bar does, that view isn't
但是视图目前
prepared to do.
做不到的
So, we need some way of adapting
所以我们需要一些解决
that.
方法
And that's what this
这也是这个
NSTouchBarItem class does.
NSTouchBarItem 类的目的
So, it binds a view to the Touch
它将一个 视图 结合到了
Bar.
Touch Bar 中
NSTouchBarItem itself is a very
NSTouchBarItem 是一个非常基础的
basic class.
类
It's intended to be sub classed
它是一个子类
and that's probably not
你们可能也
something you're actually going
不会真的用到
to have to do.
它
Because AppKit includes about
因为 AppKit 包含了
half a dozen existing Touch Bar
大约 6 个 Touch Bar 子类
subclasses that will handle a
可以满足
lot of the needs you're going to
你们的很多
have.
需求
And finally one of the most
最后 NSTouchBarItem 类的
important features of the
一个最重要的功能是
NSTouchBarItem class is that it
他有一个能
has an identifier that uniquely
唯一标识
identifies that item and
NSTouchBar 实例里的
functionality within its
项和功能的
NSTouchBar instance.
标识符
So, let's talk about NSTouchBar
让我们来说说 NSTouchBar
itself.
本身
The most important thing is that
最重要的是它有
it has an array of those item
一个用于标识项的
identifiers that identify the
标识符
items.
数组
And this is important for
这对解决哪些功能
resolving what functionalities
要用在 Touch Bar 中
goes into the Touch Bar to the
用于显示的视图中
views used to display it.
是十分重要的
Let's take a quick look at a
我们来快速的看一个
code snippet.
代码片段
So, here we're going to go ahead
这里我们将要为
and just declare some
一条鲨鱼和一个海龟
identifiers for a shark and sea
声明一些
turtle.
标识符
Usually when you come up with
通常我们在为代码
identifiers for our code, we
命名标识符时 我们建议使用
recommend using reverse DNS, but
反向域名解析 但是
these are a little bit more
这样会更加
legible.
清晰
And once we have those
一旦我们有了这些标识符
identifiers, we're going to go
我们将
ahead and instantiate a new
实例化一个新的
NSTouchBar and just set the
NSTouchBar 然后
default the item identifiers
将项标识符数组设为
array.
默认值
And this let's AppKit know what
这样可以让 AppKit 知道
sort of semantic functionality
我们把什么语义功能
we're putting in the Touch Bar.
放到了 Touch Bar 里
What we're going to cover now is
我们现在要讲的是
how AppKit resolves that.
AppKit 如何解决这个问题
And there's two ways we do this
我们有两个方法能
look up.
进行查找
There's two ways we find
我们有两种方法能够
NSTouchBarItem from the item
从项标识符里找出
identifiers.
NSTouchBarItem
And the first is a property on
第一种是一个叫做 templateItems 的
NSTouchBar called template
NSTouchBar
items.
属性
And this is just a set of items.
这只是一个项的集合
So, if we go back to some code
如果我们回头看看代码片段
snippets, this is what we had
这与我们之前编写的代码
before, exactly the same, and
完全相同
we've added some.
然后我们做一些添加
So, here I'm using an
这里我给鲨鱼
NSCustomTouchBar item class for
和海龟分别用了一个
the shark and turtles
NSCustomTouchBar
respectively.
的项类
And this is one of those
这是我之前提到的
subclasses I mentioned.
那些子类的其中一个
And we're just setting the view
现在我们将项的视图
of these items to an NS button.
设置为“NSButton”
And we go ahead and we make the
接下来我们来处理标题
title, you know the shark emoji
就像鲨鱼或者海龟
or the turtle emoji.
表情符号那样
You'll notice we're using the NS
你会注意到我们用到的是
button convenience constructor
在 macOS10.12 里介绍到的
we introduced in macOS 10.12,
NSButton 简便构造方法
and that's important because
十分重要 因为
these convenience constructors
这些简便构造方法
will configure the buttons to be
可以使 NSButton 变成外观敏感的
appearance sensitive to use the
从而能使用
right styling and font.
正确的样式和字体
And if we build an NS button
如果我们直接构建 NSButton
directly, we may not get that
我们可能不会得到这个
functionality.
功能
So, this is a big time saver.
这可以大大节省时间
But, finally after instantiating
最后在项目实例化后
these items, we're just going to
我们要
go ahead and stuff them in the
将它们添加到
template item set.
templateItems 集合里
And if we do all of this, we're
如果我们做完了
going to wind up with the Touch
所有步骤 我们将在
Bar we see at the bottom of the
屏幕底部的 Touch Bar 上看到
screen, with our shark button
鲨鱼按钮和
and our turtle button.
海龟按钮
Something I'd like to mention,
我想要提到一件事是
if you go ahead and copy and
如果你将代码拷贝粘贴到
paste the code on the slide into
Swift Playground 里 XCode 将
a Swift playground, XCode will
对我们创建的
go ahead and preview the Touch
Touch Bar 项及
Bar items we construct and the
Touch bar 本身
Touch Bar itself.
进行预览
And this is a pretty useful way
这是一种能快速
of rapidly prototyping your
建立你的 Touch Bar UI 原型的
Touch Bar UIs.
有效方式
So, that's template items.
好了  templateItems 的内容就这么多
Let's go ahead and cover what we
现在我们来看看
can do with the delegate.
我们能用委托干些什么
So, there's a single delegate
在 NSTouchBarDelegate 协议里
method in the NSTouchBarDelegate
有一个单独的委托
protocol.
方法
And that's Touch Bar,
那就是 Touch Bar 的
makeItemForIdentifier.
makeItemForIdentifier
And it's pretty simple.
它非常简单
If we take a look at this code
如果我们看看这里的代码
here, this is exactly the same
会发现它和 templateItems
as the template items case.
的情况一模一样
What's different is we've
不同之处在于我们
structured it in a switch
将它放在一个 Switch 语句里
statement, so we can go ahead
当 AppKit 要查找一个
and conditionally create a new
特殊的标识符时
item when AppKit asks for one of
我们能有条件地
our specific identifiers.
创建一个新项
AppKit cahces the result of this
AppKit 会缓存这个方法的
method.
结果
So, you really can just treat
所以 你完全可以将它看作一个
this as a factory and make a new
工厂 每次都创建一个
instance each time.
新的实例
You don't have to maintain a
除非在其他地方有用
back pointer yourself, unless
否则你无须自己
that's useful for other reasons.
保留一个反向指针
Something else that's important
我要讲的另一个重点是
to mention is, you know I've
我已经提到了一些
covered customizability a little
关于自定义的内容
bit, and let's take that Touch
现在就让我们来
Bar we've made and make it
对我做的 Touch Bar 进行
customizable.
自定义
So, that involves adding a few
这包括增加一些
things.
东西
The first bit is actually this
首先是在第一行的内容
top line, where we go ahead and
我们在这里要把 NSApp
tell NS application to set
设置为 isAutomaticCustomize
isAutomaticCustomize
TouchBarMenuItem
TouchBarMenuItemEnabled.
Enabled
That's a mouthful, but it's
这很拗口 但是
actually a very simply way of
这是一种非常简单的
handling this.
处理方法
If you set this to true,
如果你将它设置为真
NSApplication is going to go
NSApp 将为你
ahead and create a menu item for
自动生成一个目录项
you automatically that will show
可以用于展示
and hide the customization
和隐藏自定义
panel.
面板
You don't have to use that.
你不需要用到它
NSApplication has a method to
NSApp 有一种
show and hide it explicitly and
方法能明确的展示和隐藏它
you can wire that up to your
如果你希望多一些控制
menu item if you want a little
你可以将它加入你的
bit more control.
目录项
But with that out of the way,
讲完了这些
let's look at the bottom of the
我们来看幻灯片
code in this slide, where we set
底部的这行代码 我们在这里设置
the customization identifier.
自定义的标识符
And in this case, I'm just
在这种情况下
making up an ocean animal
我来编写一个海洋生物的
identifier.
标识符
But it's important to set this,
设置它是很重要的
because this is the token which
因为这是个令牌
enables persistence of the Touch
能使 Touch Bar 的配置在
Bar configuration across
应用程序的开始
launches of your application or
或者系统的重启时
reboots of the system.
得以持续
And there's one other important
启用自定义的
step for enabling customization,
另一个重要步骤是
and that is to set this
设置 customization
customizationAllowedItem
AllowedItemIdentifier
Identifiers array.
的数组
And we're just going ahead and
我们现在重新设置
set it to our shark and sea
我们的鲨鱼和
turtle again.
海龟
But setting this allows the
这个设置能让
customization panel to know
自定义面板知道
which items can be added and
哪些项可以被添加 哪些要被
removed.
移除
If we do all of that, we can
如果我们做完了所有这些
bring up the customization panel
我们可以打开自定义面板
and we'll see exactly this, the
我们将看到
defaultItemIdentifiers array is
defaultItemIdentifiers 数组被
translated faithfully to the
转化成为
default set of items on the
左边的
left.
一组项
And the individual items from
被允许的项标识符
the allowed item identifiers are
中的个别项
shown on the right.
将显示在右边
This is kind of a boring
这是个很乏味的
customization panel and we can
自定义面板 我们来
spice it up a little.
使它有变得有趣一些
So, here's a whole menagerie of
这里有一整个动物园的
ocean animals.
海洋动物
Something I want to mention, and
我想说的是
it will come into play with
在创建项模板的时候
deciding whether you're going to
你需要决定你要
set the template items on a
将它设置在 Touch Bar 上
Touch Bar when you create it, or
还是使用
whether to use the delegate is
默认的委托
by default we were only showing
只显示鲨鱼和海龟
the shark and sea turtle.
这时他就会起作用
And there's a lot of
在很多应用中
applications where your default
你的 Touch Bar 上的
functionality in the Touch Bar
默认功能只是
is going to be a very small
你在自定义时
subset of the total
可添加的所有功能
functionality you can add
中的很小一
through customization.
部分
By using the delegate, users who
通过使用委托
don't bring up the customization
不使用自定义面板的用户
panel aren't going to pay the
就不会浪费 CPU 时间
CPU time of creating new items.
创建新项
Something else to mention here
另一件需要注意的事是
is you may have a situation
在某些情况下
where you're building a Touch
你可能想要创建
Bar UI and there's some
一个 Touch Bar UI
functionality you want to be
其中的有些功能
there all the time, you don't
你希望它一直存在
want the user to be able to
不希望用户在自定义区
remove it in customization, and
移除它
if you have a case like that you
如果你遇到这样的问题
can set the customization
你可以设置自定义
required item identifiers array.
所需的项标识符数组
And in this case, obviously, the
这样的情况下 显然
sea turtle is critical for the
海龟对我们的应用功能
function of our application.
很关键
So, we're going to prevent it
所以 我们要避免它
from being removed.
被移除
So, that kind of covers how to
好了 这基本涵盖了怎样
make instances of NSTouchBar and
制作 NSTouchBar 实例
how to facilitate item lookup by
以及怎么通过
the item identifier, through the
模板项和委托方法
template items and delegate
使用用项标识符来帮助项目
methods.
查找
But one of the things we're
有一样东西我们漏掉了
missing is how the applicant
那就是 App
finds those instances of
如何能够找到 NSTouchBar
NSTouchBar.
的实例
And I big part of that is the
这里很重要的一个部分是
NSTouchBarProvider protocol.
NSTouchBarProvider 协议
And it's a fairly simple
这是一个很简单的
protocol.
协议
It's just exposing a read-only
它揭示了 Touch Bar 的一个
Touch Bar property.
只读属性
NSResponder itself implements
NSResponder 创新性的
this protocol right out of the
执行了这个
box.
协议
And we'll cover that in just a
这个我们一会儿将会
second.
谈到
But sometimes it's useful to
有时候将 Touch Bar 加到
attach a Touch Bar to your
你的应用委托
application delegate, or window
或者窗口委托是
delegate.
有用的
And neither of those is likely
它们中任何一个都
to be a subclass of NSResponder.
不是 NSResponder 的子类
So, let's see how you go ahead
让我们来看看
and implement that protocol
你将如何执行这个
yourself.
协议
This looks like a lot of code,
这起来和很多其他的代码一样
but really we're just using a
但是我们只是用到了 Touch Bar 的属性中
Swift lazy variable here for the
的 Swift 延迟
Touch Bar property.
变量
And the first time the Touch Bar
当 Touch Bar 第一次被访问时
property is accessed, Swift is
Swift 就会开始
going to go ahead and run this
运行代码块
block to instantiate our Touch
并实例化
Bar.
Touch Bar
All the code to create the item
也就是我们在上一张幻灯片里看到的
in bar and stuff we looked at in
在 Touch Bar 和别的地方创建项
the previous slides.
的那些代码
Something else to mention is
还需要提及的是
that AppKit key value observes
AppKit Key 值可以监测
this property.
这个属性
So, if you feel the need to
如果你需要
replace your Touch Bar
完全移除 Touch Bar
wholesale, we'll notice that
我们将注意到
sort of change.
这个改变
Let's look at how NSResponder
让我们看看 NSResponder
implements this.
如何执行它
First, it exposes that Touch Bar
首先 它表明 touchBar 属性
property as a read-write
是一个可读写的属性
property instead of read-only.
而不是只读的
And the significance of that is
它的重要性在于你可以
that you can set instances of
在你应用的不同部分设置
NSTouchBar on various pieces of
NSTouchBar
your application.
实例
On the responders, you have in
你可以在响应器的窗口
your windows.
上看到
Like views and view controllers,
就像视图 视图控制器
and window controllers.
和窗口控制器那样
And that's really neat because
这非常简单 因为
you don't necessarily have a
你不用为每个
subclass for each and every one
控件创建
of those controls.
子类
If you are making a subclass of
如果你为控件或
a control, or really any
任何 NSResponder 创建了子类
NSResponder, NSResponder also
NSResponder 同样会
exposes this makeTouchBar
暴露 makeTouchBar()
method.
方法
So, makeTouchBar is pretty
所以 makeTouchBar() 是非常
simple.
简单的
The first time the Touch Bar
touchBar 属性第一次
property is accessed on an
接入 NSResponder 时
NSResponder, it's going to call
它将调用 makeTouchBar() 并
self makeTouchBar and run this
运行此
code.
代码
And we just have to return a new
这时我们只用返回一个新的
Touch Bar for it.
Touch Bar 给它
A lot of the system controls and
很多系统控件和
system frameworks, which expose
系统框架都使用这种方法
functionality use this method to
暴露他们的
provide it.
功能
So, I mentioned that NSResponder
就像我提到的那样 NSResponder
has a read-write Touch Bar
有一个读写属性
property and you can set the
大家可以对它进行
touch bar.
设置
And one of the most important
其中一个很重要的
clients of that is actually
受众就是
Interface Builder.
Interface Builder
So, let me show you how to build
让我来向大家展示如何通过
a Touch Bar UI from Interface
Interface Builder 创建一个
Builder.
Touch Bar UI
If we go ahead and start with a
如果我们从
new story board, we have a
Story Board 开始
window controller seen here, and
我们可以看到一个窗口控制器
we can filter the object library
然后我们可以通过过滤对象库
to show us Touch Bar controls.
来展示 Touch Bar 控件
So, if we just check the object
所以如果我们检查对象库
library, here an instance of NS
这里有一个 NSTouchBar 的实例
Touch Bar and we can drag that
我们可以将它拖到
onto our window controller.
窗口控制器上
And now we have an empty Touch
现在我们得到了一个空的
Bar to play with and going back
Touch Bar
to the object library, we can go
回到对象库
ahead and see that there's
我们可以看到一打打的
dozens and dozens of
预配置的控件
preconfigured controls and Touch
和 Touch Bar 项
Bar items we can just drag into
我们可以把它拖到
the Touch Bar.
Touch Bar 里
And from here, we can wire these
从现在起 我们
items up with ID connections, or
就可以用 ID 连接或者捆绑来
bindings or whatever.
写这些项了
And it's actually very possible
其实 不写一行代码
to write Touch Bar apps that are
就使 Touch Bar 应用
perfectly functional and useable
能进行完美的工作
without ever writing a line of
和使用是非常
code for it.
可能的
So, that covers creating
我们讲完了创建
instances of NSTouchBarItem.
NSTouchBarItem 实例
Let's see how this fits into the
现在让我们来看 它将如何适应
bigger responder chain and how
大的响应器链 以及我们
we discover all of these
如何发现所有的 Touch Bar
individual Touch Bar instances.
个体实例
So, a refresher, a responder
一个刷新控件
chain is made up of instances of
一个响应器链是由
the NSResponder class.
NSResponder 类的实例组成的
And one of the most important
NSResponder 类中最重要
properties of the NSResponder
的属性就是它的
class is this next responder
下一个响应器的
property it has.
属性
And that just points at another
这指向了另一个
responder.
响应器
But it basically means that
这意味着给定一个响应器
given a responder, we've
我们就能链接
anchored an entire chain of
整条响应器链并使其能
responders capable of handling
处理事件
events and actions and things.
行动和别的东西
And AppKit uses many different
AppKit 用很多不同的
responders as the anchors for
响应器作为链条的锚
chains for handling keyboard
来处理键盘事件
events, and actions and kit
对行为和点击的测试
testing and routing mouse events
以及常规的鼠标事件。
and things, but let's cover how
我们来讲讲
keyboard event works.
键盘事件如何工作
Because Touch Bar is part of the
因为 Touch Bar 是键盘的
keyboard.
一部分
So, we're going to have an
系统将交给我们
NSEvent handed to us by the
一个 NSEvent 事件
system, and that's going to go
随后这个事件
over the NSApplication.
将返回 NSApplication
And NSApplication is going to
NSApplication 将告知我们
say what do I do with this
要对键盘事件
keyboard event.
做什么
And most NSApplications are
大多数 NSApplication 会问
going to say do I have a key
我是否有主
window?
窗口
Okay, it gets the keyboard event
好的 这就是一个键盘
now.
事件
And the key window meanwhile is
同时 主窗口也会有
going to have the same question,
同样的问题
what do I do with this keyboard
我要对键盘事件
event.
做什么
Every NS Window had a property
每一个 NSWindow 都有
called first responder and
一个叫做第一响应器的属性
that's designating where the
它能指出键盘事件在
responder chain starts for
响应器链条的
keyboard events and actions and
什么位置开始启动
things.
等等
So, the key window is going to
所以 主窗口
go ahead and say, all right
会说 好的
let's send this event to my
我们来将它发送到我的第一响应器
first responder, like in its key
就像它在按下和释放键盘
down or key up method.
方法里一样
So, the first responder
这很有趣
meanwhile it's interesting,
第一响应器是我们锚定响应链
because that's where it's
的位置 是我们将要
anchoring the responder chain,
像响应器方法那样
where we're going to be handling
处理它的地方
this as a responder method, not
而不仅仅是
just generic event routing.
通用路由事件
But it's going to have a
它将作出一个决定
decision, do I handle the event
我是在按下键盘的时候
in key down, or do I call super
处理事件 还是调用父类
and let it pass that to the next
然后让它传递给下一个
responder.
响应器
So, let's say it passes it to
我们假设它传递到了
the next responder.
下一个响应器
Usually the first responder will
一般来说 第一个响应是一个视图
be a view, the second responder
第二个响应器
will be a super view.
是一个父视图
It will make the same choice.
它会作出同样的选择
And these days, use and view
目前 视图和
controllers tend to be
视图控制器一般
[inaudible] in the responder
是在响应器链
chain.
里面的
So, pass it up to a view
所以 将它传递给视图控制器
controller, have the same choice
同样会使 Handler
handler call super.
调用父类
It doesn't handle it.
它不会处理它
It might even go and reach all
它可能会回到
the way back to the initial
最初引起
window that routed the event in
路由事件
the first place.
的窗口
And that, as part of the
从而 它作为
responder chain, can make the
响应器链条的一部分
same decisions whether to handle
可以决定是处理
it or pass it on.
还是传递它
And that can percolate all the
这能将它滤回
way back up to the application.
应用
So, that's how we handle
这就是我们处理键盘
keyboard events.
事件的方法
Touch Bar is part of the
Touch Bar 是键盘的
keyboard.
一部分
So, it also turns out these are
这也表明 这些是我们可以
all the places we can attach
添加
instances of NSTouchBar.
NSTouchBar 实例的位置
And we search them in exactly
我们以
the same order the keyboard
与在响应器链里的路由
event was routed through the
键盘事件相同的顺序
responder chain.
来查找它们
So, one question you should be
所以 你应该问的问题是
asking is hey, I notice you have
嘿 我注意到你有
five instances of NSTouchBar
5 个 NSTouchBar
here.
实例
How do you go from that to one
你要如何将它们
Touch Bar on the device.
放在设备上的 Touch Bar 上
And I'm going to cover that in
我马上会讲到这个
just a second.
问题
But first I want to make a small
但是首先 我想谈谈
note about views and views
视图和视图
controllers.
控制器
You're probably going to be
你可能会在某个时候需要
attaching a Touch Bar to a view
将 Touch Bar 加到视图控制器上
controller at some point, making
来制作你的
your application.
应用程序
And you'll run and test this.
你会运行并测试
And you're going to see that
然后你会发现
your Touch Bar doesn't show up
Touch Bar 完全没有显示
at all and you'll think, oh, I
这时你会想
guess my view controller is not
我猜我的视图控制器不在
in the responder chain.
响应器链上
And you'll go ahead and look at
你会去查看你的视图控制器
your view controllers view and
你会发现下一个响应器
see that its next responder is
确实就是你的
indeed your view controller.
视图控制器
And what's going on here is that
这里发生的事是
while your particular responder
当特定的响应器链
chain is set up correctly, it's
被正确的设置，
not anchored in the first
它不是在窗口的第一响应器
responder of the window.
里被锚定
And that's often because the
那通常是因为
first responder of the window
窗口的第一响应器
has to return true for the
必须对 acceptsFirstResponder 方法
acceptsFirstResponder method.
返回真
So, if you wind up in this
如果你在这种情况下结束
situation, it's really easy to
很容易让你的第一响应器
subclass NS View or whatever
去继承 NSView 或第一响应器
your first responder is to
将要接受的内容并
accept first responder and make
做出一个锚定在
a valid responder chain anchored
第一响应器里的
at the first responder.
有效的响应器链
So, let's get back to how we're
让我们回到
going to handle multiple
如何在这里处理多个
NSTouchBar instances on this.
NSTouchBar 实例
The easiest thing to remember is
最简单的是记住
that the responder, with an
如果一个 NSTouchBar
NSTouchBar closest to that first
距离第一响应器
responder, so closest to the
很近 也就是离
keyboard input, its Touch Bar is
键盘输入很近 它的 Touch Bar
going to win and take over the
将会胜利并
whole thing.
取代其他
Calling back to earlier where I
回忆一下我之前提到的
mentioned that AVKit and some
AVKit 和其他系统框架
other system frameworks provide
能提供支持
support, you're probably
你可能
thinking that they're likely
会认为它们
going to provide support in NS
会为距离第一响应器
Views which are going to be
更近的 NS View
closer to the first responder
提供支持
than your window controllers or
而不是为你的窗口控制器或者
application delegates might be.
应用程序委托
So, we need some way of sharing
所以我们需要能
the device Touch Bar across
在多个 NSTouchBar 实例中分享
multiple instances of NSTouchBar
Touch Bar 设备的方法
and we have a way of doing that.
我们有这样的方法
And that's accomplished with
那就是用
this special item identifier,
一个叫做 otherItemsProxy 的
called the otherItemsProxy.
特殊的项标识符来完善它
I say it's a special item
我称它为特殊项
identifier because you don't
标识符因为
have to create any item for
你不用为它创建
this.
任何项
You don't have to put it in your
你不用将它放到你的
template item set, you don't
模板项组里
have to handle that identifier
你不必在委托里
in your delegate and make item
操作标识符 然后为标识符
for identifier case.
创建项
But when you go ahead and
但当你将代理服务器
include other items proxy in
添加到
your default item identifier
你的默认项标识符组里
array, when AppKit is harvesting
当 AppKit 从响应器链里
NSTouchBar from the responder
收到 NSTouchBar 时
chain, it will go ahead and
它将用
replace the otherItemsProxy with
距离第一响应器
the items from responders closer
更近的项来代替
to the first responder.
otherItemsProxy
So, let's look at that in
我们来用实际操作来了解
action.
一下
Here's an example of mail.
这里是一个“邮件”的例子
My keyboard focus is on the
我的光标
recipient's field.
在收件人栏
And the recipient's field is
收件人栏可以
providing suggestions for who I
为我要向谁发送邮件
might to send the email to.
提供建议
I also have this send button on
我在 Touch Bar
the left side of the application
应用部分的左侧
section of the Touch Bar.
有一个发送按钮
If I were to change my keyboard
如果我将我的光标
focus instead to the composition
移到窗口中的
view in the window, I have a
组合视图 我将有
bunch of text formatting
很多文本排版控件
controls and an emoji picker.
和一个表情符号选择器
But I still have that send
但是我仍然有那个发送
button.
按钮
And the way this breaks down is
这个过程分解开来就是
that mail's composed window
组织邮件的窗口控制器
controller has a Touch Bar with
有一个带有发送键
a send button and an
和 otherItemsProxy 的
otherItemsProxy.
Touch Bar
And the recipient's field is
然后收件人栏
providing the candidates.
会提供候选人
very close to the first
距离很近
responder, so it's going to get
所以它会先
first shot at that.
执行
But the window controller
但是窗口控制器
including the otherItemsProxy
包括 otherItemsProxy
means we can merge those two
意味着我们可以合并这两个
Touch Bars.
Touch Bar
Likewise, for the composition
同样的 对于组合视图
view, the window controller is
窗口控制器
exactly the same instance, it's
是完全相同的实例
just the responder chain
只不过响应器链锚定在
anchored at the first responder
第一响应器
includes the composition view
包括在窗口控制器之前
before the window controller.
的组合视图
Something else to mention is
需要提到的是
that this is completely
这和自定义功能
compatible with customization.
是完全兼容的
We use the otherItemsProxy to
就像你期待的那样
build the default set of items,
我们用 otherItemsProxy
like you'd expect.
来创建项目的默认设置
And we go ahead and union the
我们从合适的
allowed items from the eligible
Touch Bar 里聚合
touch bars.
被允许项
So, we can see we can customize
所以我们看到 我们可以
the send button in mail, even
在邮件里自定义发送键
though it's provided by a
尽管是用
different responder than the
不同的响应器
formatting controls.
而不是排版控件
You might think, hey the
你可能会想 诶
otherItemsProxy sounds pretty
otherItemsProxy 听起来
great for the reliable
是个很适合
functioning of my Touch Bar
Touch Bar 的东西
stuff, and you'd be right, but
你可能是对的 但是
there's a few cases where you do
有些时候
want to omit it.
你应该忽略它
And if we go back to mail, but
我们回到邮件
close all the windows, we're
关掉所有窗口
going to see that we have a new
我们会看到有
viewer window button in the
一个新的视图窗口出现在
Touch Bar.
Touch Bar 里
And that's provided by the
这是由应用提供的
application, but it omits the
但它省略了
otherItemsProxy.
otherItemsProxy
When we go ahead and bring a
当我们调出
window up that has Touch Bar
一个有 Touch Bar 的窗口
content it's going to be closer
它会距离
to the first responder, and the
第一响应器近
lack of the otherItemsProxy in
Touch Bar 里没有
the farther out Touch Bar means
otherItemsProxy 意味着
it gets replaced entirely.
它被完全替代了
So, there's another sort of
另一种我想讲到的
special item identifier I want
特殊项标识符
to cover and those are spaces.
则是间距
So, if you see here, we've made
这里 我们已经制作了
a mockup Touch Bar and we have a
一个仿制的 Touch Bar
shark item and an angelfish.
我们有一个鲨鱼和
And the angel fish probably
一个天使鱼项
isn't that comfortable being so
天使鱼可能不想
close to the shark.
太靠近鲨鱼
Thankfully, the shark is facing
谢天谢地 鲨鱼面朝
the wrong way so the fish
错误的方向
probably isn't on the menu yet.
所以鱼可能还不在菜单里
But we can go ahead and give the
但是我们能给
angelfish some breathing room.
天使鱼一点呼吸空间
And we can do that by adding a
我们可以在
fixed space small item
鲨鱼和天使鱼之间
identifier in the default item
的默认项标识符组里
identifiers array in between the
加入一个
shark and angelfish item
固定间距的
identifiers.
小项标识符
And we don't have to settle for
我们不一定用小的
small, we can also use a large
我们也可以用大的
one and give it a little bit
来给它更多
more space.
间距
And it's useful to use these
这比对你的间距
instead of hard coding your own
进行硬编码有用
space, because these are our
因为
system defined values that may
我们系统定义的值
change from release to release,
会随着一次次发布而改变
but they also give your app an
这会使你的 App 和
appearance similar to other apps
系统里别的 App 看起来
on the system.
非常相似
We don't have to stop with fixed
不过我们不需要用
spaces though, we also have a
固定间距来阻止它
flexible space identifier.
我们同样有自动调整间距的标识符
And the flexible space is
有趣的是 自动调整间距
interesting in that it's going
会将
to push the adjacent items as
邻近的项
far away from each other as they
能推多远就
can get.
推多远
So, in this case, the angelfish
在这种情况下
probably feels a lot better with
天使鱼可能觉得自动调整
that flexible space between it
它和鲨鱼之间的间距更
and the shark.
舒服一些
You might be thinking you could
你可能认为你可以
put flexible space on two side
将自动调整间距放在项的两侧
of an item to center it.
使项目居中
And that's a very reasonable
你有充分的理由
thought.
这样想
If you do that, you're going,
如果要这样做
actually, let's say we do that
比如我们这样
with our purple circle.
处理一下紫色圆圈
We put flexible space on the
我们在它的左右两边
left and right sides of it.
放置可调整的间距
The circle is centered within
你可能会使圆圈在
the application section of the
Touch Bar 应用程序区里居中
Touch Bar, which might be what
这可能是你
you're going for.
想做的
But you might also want to be
但是你可能同样
centering that item on the
希望使这个项在真正的设备上
actual device, and it's not
也居中 但并它不在
there.
那里
We're a little bit to the left.
我们稍微有些偏右了
So, we can fix that by using and
所以我们可以通过用
NSTouchBar property called the
一个叫主要项标识符的
principal item identifier.
NSTouchBar 属性来解决它
And we can go ahead and set a
我们可以将
Touch Bar's
Touch Bar 的
principalItemIdentifier to the
主要项标识符设置成
identifier of any visible item,
任何可视项的标识符
and it's going to go ahead and
它就会将此项
actually place that item in the
置于设备
center of the device.
的中间位置
So, if we go ahead and look at
当我们看这个例子时
this example, all the code in
这里所有的代码都是
here is stuff we see in our
我们在前一张幻灯片里看到过的
previous slides except this last
除了我们被设置过的
line where we set the
主要项标识符的
principalItemIdentifier.
最后一行
And by setting to the shark
通过设置鲨鱼标识符
identifier, we go ahead and move
我们将鲨鱼放到
and the shark to the middle of
Touch Bar 的中间
the Touch Bar and lay out the
然后就像我们在别处做的一样
items left to right like we did
将项从左到右
in other cases.
摆放
If we were to use the turtle
如果我们要改用海龟
instead, the shark winds up on
鲨鱼像之前一样
the left side like it would
被放在左边
normally, and the turtle is
然后海龟会被
centered on the device.
放在设备的中间
And this plays really well with
这在自动设置间距和
flexible spaces and other
某些其他情况
things.
表现得很好
Son you can make some nuance
所以你可以用它来制作
device with that.
一些小的设备
And there's additionally types
还有其他种类的
of NSTouchBar items subclasses
能修改主要项标识符
that modify the behavior of the
行为的 NSTouchBar
principalItemIdentifier.
子项
And John is going to go ahead
接下来 John 将为大家
and cover those as we take a
深入地讲解
deep dive into NSTouchBar item.
NSTouchBar 项
Welcome John Tegtmeyer.
欢迎 John Tegtmeyer
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, Chris gave us an overview
Chris 向我们介绍了
over the NSTouchBar API and how
NSTouchBar API 以及它如何
it's tied to the responder chain
通过连接响应器链
allowing us to provide context
让我们为用户提供
sensitive controls to our users.
上下文敏感控件
He also eluded to this
他也提到了
NSTouchBar item object, which is
NSTouchBar 项目对象
the wrap around all the views in
是环绕 Touch Bar 里所有
the Touch Bar.
视图的
Now, AppKit provides a lot of
现在 AppKit
subclasses of this item, and
提供项的许多子项
they all offer some really
他们都能提供一些
unique, very cool functionality.
非常特殊的 很酷的功能
So, I'm here to give us a deep
现在我来为大家深入的
dive into those items.
讲解一下这些项
NSTouchBar item is a base class
NSTouchBar 项是我们
of everything that we'll talk
今天谈论的所有东西的
about today.
基本项
That means the properties on
这代表它的设置
this will be inherited by the
会被子项所
subclass.
继承
The first thing that all Touch
所有 Touch Bar 项都有的
Bar items have is a unique
东西就是唯一
identifier.
标识符
This is what NSTouchBar will use
这就是 NSTouchBar 用来
when looking up your item
通过模板项数组
through the template items
或委托来查找项的
array, or through the delegate.
东西
Items also have a view or a view
项也有视图或者视图
controller.
控制器
This is what's actually
这也是实际上会
presented to your users.
展示给用户的东西
And if you're using the view
如果你在使用视图
controller, this is a good
控制器 这是延迟
opportunity to lazily load your
加载视图的
views.
好机会
We also have a customization
我们同样有自定义
label.
标签
And this is the string that's
这是显示在
presented in the customization
自定义 UI 上的
UI.
字符串
And describes what your control
它定义了你的控件能
actually does.
做什么
I hope you notice one thing that
我希望你们注意到了
we don't have here is an
在这里我们没有的是
explicit minimum or maximum size
明确的最小或最大的
property.
属性
That's because, unlike tool bar
这是因为 不同于
item, which does have these
工具栏项确实具有这些
explicit properties Touch Bar
明确的属性
items are actually measured
NSTouchBarItem 的度量
using constraints.
是有限制的
That means if you're using
这意味着 如果你
something like an NS button
使用一个有 intrinsicContentSize 的
which has an intrinsic content
类似 NSButton 的东西
size, it will automatically be
它将自动调整大小
sized to fit its title and its
以适应标题和
image.
图像
You can also choose to use
你也可以选择使用
inequality constraints to set up
不等式约束去设置
minimum and maximum sizes.
最大及最小尺寸
And AppKit will automatically
AppKit 将基于
size you view based on how much
应用程序区可用的距离
space is available in the
来自动调整视图
application section.
大小
And you can find out more about
你可以在今天晚些时候的
how items are sized at the
“Advanced Touch Bar（Touch Bar 进阶）”演讲上听到
"Advanced Touch Bar Talk" later
更多关于项目大小的
today.
内容
Now, as I mentioned, AppKit
现在 就像我之前提到的一样
provides lots of subclasses of
AppKit 提供了很多的
this item.
项子类
And we'll talk about each of
我们将逐个进行
these.
讲解
We'll talk about the custom
我们将谈到
Touch Bar item, pop overs,
Touch Bar 自定义项 弹窗
sliders, group item, as well as
滑动条 组项 以及在最后会提到的
a few bonus topics at the end.
几个额外的话题
So, let's get started with the
好的 让我们从 Touch Bar 的
custom Touch Bar item.
自定义项开始
Now, the custom item offers
现在自定义项为我们
rewrite properties on everything
刚才提到的所有基类上
that we just talked about on the
的东西提供了重写
base class.
属性
That means you can simply set
这意味着你可以简单地
the view of the view controller
对视图控制器的视图进行设置
rather than subclassing your
而不是子类化你的
item.
项
This is likely the item that
如果你想展示一个按钮
you'll use if you want to show
或者一个分段选择控件
something like a button or a
或者任何你熟悉的
segmented control.
AppKit 或者
Anything that you're familiar
自定义容器视图
with through AppKit, or custom
你都可以使用
container views.
它
Now, this is also a really great
这也是使用 10.12 中
opportunity to use some of the
引入的便利
convenience constructors that we
构造函数的
introduced in 10.12.
好机会
Let's take a look.
让我们来看看
In this example, we're going to
在这个例子里
create a simple button for Touch
我们将为 Touch Bar 创建一个简单的
Bar.
按钮
We're doing that by creating a
我们通过创建
custom Touch Bar item and
自定义 Touch Bar 项以
providing a unique identifier.
提供唯一标识符来实现
And then we're going to set the
我们将会用之前看到的
items view to be an NS button
title: target: action: 格式构造函数
using the title target action
来将项的视图
constructor that we saw earlier.
设置为 NSButton
And as Chris mentioned, this
就像 Chris 提到的
will assign the correct font and
这将把正确的字体和
the correct appearance to this
正确的外观赋值给这个
button.
按钮
So, we have a great looking
我们用两行简单的代码
button that's ready for Touch
为 Touch Bar 创建了
Bar in two simple lines of code.
一个漂亮的按钮
This is also true for a more
这对更加复杂的控件也
complicated control.
适用
In this case, this is a
在这里 这是一个
segmented control.
分段控制器
Segmented control also has a
分段控制器同时有一个
convenience constructor.
便利构造器
And so, again with two lines of
同样用两行代码
code, my spacing for clarity, we
我为了看起来更清晰所以将它间隔开
have a great looking control
为 Touch Bar 创建了一个
that's ready for Touch Bar with
有正确外观
the right appearance and the
和字体的美观
right font.
控件
Next, let's talk about popovers.
下面 我们来谈谈弹出框
Popover item is really cool
弹出框项很酷
because it allows you to provide
因为它能在用户要求的时候
extra content to your user, but
为用户提供
only when the user requests it.
更多内容
Popovers have two parts.
弹出框分两个部分
The first is the class
第一部分是折叠形式
representation, which is the
是当弹出框关闭时
view presented to your user when
展示给用户的
the popovers close.
视图
And the second piece is the
第二部分是
popover's NSTouchBar, which
弹出框的 NSTouchBar
actually takes over the
当弹出框打开的时候
application section when the
它会接管
popover is open.
应用程序区
And this lets you use things
这让你能够使用
like the
principalItemIdentifier
principalItemIdentifier, or even
甚至让你能进行
enabling customization.
自定义
Let's talk more about the class
让我们多谈谈
representation.
折叠形式
AppKit will provide a default on
AppKit 将给你提供一个默认值
for you and you can customize
你能通过折叠形式的
the way it looks by using the
图像或者标签
class representation image, or
属性来进行
label properties.
自定义
And you can see an example of
你可以在弹出框队列
this in the list in alignment
和排版控件里
popovers and the formatting
看到这种
controls.
例子
You can also choose to use
你也可以选择
something more custom.
使用更加自定义的东西
Mail chooses to use a segmented
“邮件”选择使用分段
control.
控制器
And if you tap the main portion
如果你点击这个控件的主要部分
of this control, it will
它马上将
immediately move a message to
消息移动到建议的
the suggest mailbox.
邮箱里
But if you tap the arrow, it
但是如果你点击箭头 它
will show a popover with
将出现一个有
additional suggestions.
额外建议的弹出框
This is actually really easy to
这其实非常容易做到
achieve by providing your own
你只需要给折叠形式
view for the class
提供你的视图
representation and then using
然后使用显示弹出框
the show popover and dismiss
和隐藏弹出框
popover methods.
的方法
Popovers also have two
弹出框也有两个
interaction models.
交互模型
First is touch and show.
第一个是触摸并显示
This happens when the user taps
当用户点击折叠形式时
the class representation.
会用到这个
The popover's opened and it's
弹出框被打开
sticky allowing you to make
它的粘性让你能做出
multiple selections.
多种选择
It's only closed when the user
它只在用户点击关闭
taps the closed button.
按钮的时候才会关闭
The second interaction model is
第二个交互模型是
press and hold.
按住并保持
And this happens when the user
它在用户按住并保持
presses and holds on the class
折叠形式的时候
representation.
会用到
The popover's open directly by
弹出框可直接通过
the user's finger when possible
用户的手指打开
and immediately starts tracking
并立即开始追踪
their input.
他们的输入
It's closed when the user lifts
当用户做出选择
their finger and a selection is
并抬起手指时
made.
它就关闭了
But you'll notice that in these
你可能会注意到
two examples, the popovers
在这两个例子里
actually showed different
弹出框其实显示的是
content.
不同的内容
Touch and show showed several
触摸并显示展示了多个控件
controls whereas press and hold
而按住并保持
only showed a single segmented
则展示了单个的分段
control.
控制器
And that's because press and
这是因为触摸并显示
hold is tracking the user's
从始至终都在追踪
finger the entire time.
用户的手指
And so, it's best to leave that
所以 我们最好将
kind of interaction to a single
这种交互留给单一的
control.
控件
In this case a segmented
在这里可以是一个分段
control, or even something like
控制器 或者是一个
the slider item.
滑块
This is easy to achieve because
这很容易实现
popovers actually have two
原因是弹出框其实有两个
different NSTouchBar properties.
不同的 NSTouchBar 属性
One for the touch and hold
一个是给触摸并显示的弹出框
popover and another for the
另一个是给
press and hold.
按下并保留的
Press and hold, if you do not
如果你不为按下并保留模型
provide an NSTouchBar for press
提供一个 NSTouchBar
and hold, press and hold will
按下并保留模型
not be enabled.
就不会被启用
It is possible to provide the
这两个属性同时提供
same NSTouchBar object for both
相同的 NSTouchBar
of these properties and that
并且工作的很好
will work just fine.
是有可能的
But as I mentioned press and
但是就像我提到的 按下并保留模型
hold is best left reserved for
最好是留给
single things, single items like
类似分段控制器或者
a segmented control or a slider
滑动模块这样的
item.
单一项
Speaking of the slider item,
我们来说说
let's talk about it.
滑动模块
Now, you might be thinking
现在你可能在想
what's the difference between a
滑动模块和有 NSSlider 作为
slider item and a custom Touch
视图的自定义
Bar item with an NSSlider as its
Touch Bar 有什么
view.
区别
Well, let me explain.
我来为大家解释
Sliders have a few different
滑动模块有几个不同的
parts.
地方
First we have the slider itself.
首先 我们有滑块本身
Then, we have these new value
其次 我们有这些新的值的配件
accessories, which are images
它们是一些
and are actually intractable.
很难处理的图片
You can tap on them to increment
你可以点击它们以
or decrement the value of your
增加或减少你滑块
slider.
的值
We also have a label.
我们还有个标签
This can make it extra clear to
这能让用户
your users what this slider is
更清楚这个滑块
actually controlling.
实际上控制的是什么
And it's really useful if you
而且如果你的 UI 里有
have multiple sliders in your
多个滑块 这将十分
UI.
有用
As I mentioned these make really
就像我提到的 这为
great content for press and hold
按住并保留弹出框提供了
popover.
很好的内容
And that's because the
这是因为对
immediately start tracking the
用户手指立即进行处理
user's finger, even though the
即使触摸
touch is offset from the knob of
不发生在滑块的
the slider.
旋钮上
That means the user can
这意味着用户可以
immediately start interacting
立刻开始与之交互
with it and not go searching
而不用
around for the knob for
四处寻找旋钮来与
interacting with the slider.
滑块进行交互
Let's take a look at what this
我们来看看这在
actually looks like in code,
代码上是什么
though.
样子的
First, we're going to create the
首先 我们要创建项
item itself.
本身
We're going to provide a unique
我们要提供一个唯一
identifier.
标识符
Next, we're going to assign it
接下来 我们要为它
minimum and maximum value
赋最大和最小值的配件
accessories and we're going to
我们还要用 AppKit
use images that AppKit provides.
提供的图片
And lastly, we're going to
最后 我们要
assign a label, because maybe we
赋给他一个标签 因为我们可能
want multiple sliders in our UI.
想在 UI 上有多个滑块
But you'll notice that the
但是你会注意到
slider is actually taking up the
滑块可能会占据
entire application section.
整个应用区域
Well, that's because sliders do
因为滑块没有
not have an intrinsic content
固有内容
size.
大小
They're happy to be whatever
他们很高兴在应用区域
size is available in the
里占据任何
application section.
大小
You can change this by adding a
你可以通过
constraint to the slider and
对滑块添加一个约束来改变它
AppKit will check that and
AppKit 将检查并
automatically remeasure and
自动的重置它的
resize the item.
大小
But notice that we're doing this
但是要注意 我们是
on the slider itself, and not
在滑块本身上做这些事
the slider items view and that's
而不是滑块项的视图上
because we have a label here.
因为我们在这里有个标签
And if we change localizations
如果我们改变位置
the length of this string will
这段字符串的长度会被改变
also change and we don't want to
我们不想引起
cause clipping.
文本剪切
Next, let's talk about group
下面 我们来谈谈
Touch Bar item.
NSGroupTouchBarItem
Group item is neat because it
数据组项很简单
allows you to group multiple
因为它让你将多个
Touch Bar items into a single
Touch Bar 项组合成一个
NSTouchBarItem instance.
单一的 NSTouchBarItem 实例
This is because it's similar to
这是因为它与弹出框很像
popovers in that it offers its
都能提供它的
NSTouchBar property.
NSTouchBar 属性
An example of this is the
在我上方的排版控件
formatting controls above me.
就是这样的一个例子
These have actually been grouped
他们被组合成了一个
into a single NSTouchBarItem.
单一的 NSTouchBarItem
There are several reasons you
有很多原因可能让你做这件事
might want to do this, and we'll
我将对每一个
talk about each of these.
进行讲解
When centering multiple items,
当居中多个项时
there's some tricks you can play
你可以对自定义
with customization as well as
和定位目的使用
localization purposes.
一些技巧
If you remember a few minutes
如果你记得几分钟前
ago, when Chris was talking
Chris 讲到的
about the
principalItemIdentifier
principalItemIdentifier, you'll
你会回忆起
recall that a single item
单一的项标识符
identifier is actually provided
其实是作为主要项
as principal.
提供的
But what happens if you want to
那么如果你想像 FaceTime 一样
center multiple items together
将多个项一起居中
like FaceTime is doing here.
会发生什么
Well, you can group these items
你可以将这些项
to a single group Touch Bar item
组合成单个的 Touch Bar 组合项
and then provide that item's
然后将项的标识符
identifier as the principal item
提供为主要项
identifier.
标识符
You can also play some cool
你也可以在自定义里
tricks with the customization.
使用一些技巧
If you have a non-customizable
如果你像我们这里做的一样
group like we do here, you'll
是一个非自定义的组
notice that these items are
你会注意到这些项已经
actually grouped together.
被聚合到一起
That means when the user drags
这意味着当用户
these things into, these buttons
将这些按钮
into the Touch Bar, all three of
拖拽到 Touch Bar 里的时候
these will come together.
这三个将聚合在一起
There's also a single
这里有一个单个的
customization label describing
自定义标签将这些控件
these controls as the playback
描述为播放
controls.
控件
If you do choose to enable
如果你选择将你的组
customization on your groups,
进行自定义
you get some cool behavior there
你还将获得一些很酷的
as well.
行为
In this example, we have two
在这个例子里 我们有
group Touch Bar items.
两个 Touch Bar 项的组
Both of them have customization
他们都可以进行
enabled.
自定义
One contains a group of animals
他们一个包含一组
that you might find in the
海洋动物
ocean, and another on a farm.
另一组是农场里的动物
If I start customizing this,
如果我开始自定义
you'll notice that I'm free to
你会注意到我可以自由的
re-order these items however I
重新排序这些项
choose within their groups.
无论我在他们的组里怎么选择
If I try, however, to grab one
如果我尝试 拿出一个
of the ocean animals and put it
海洋动物然后
into the farm animals group, it
将它放到农场动物里
snaps back to where it was.
它将回跳到原来的地方
Because that would be removing
因为这是在
the item from its group and
从组里移除项
that's not supported.
这是不被支持的
GroupTouchBarItem also has
GroupTouchBarItem 对本地化
really cool purposes for
也有非常酷的
localization.
作用
Now, I'm sure your applications
现在 我很确定你的应用
reach lots of users.
有很多的用户
Some of those users might be
有些用户的母语是
native right to left speakers of
从右往左阅读的
languages like Hebrew or Arabic.
希伯来语或者阿拉伯语
And I'm sure your applications
我敢肯定你的应用
are already flipping were
已经为这些用户
appropriate for those users.
准确地调换了书写方向
And we want Touch Bar to reflect
我们希望 Touch Bar 也能反映
that as well.
出来
A good example of this is
一个很好的例子是
FaceTime's UI.
FaceTime 的 UI
FaceTime chooses to show a full
FaceTime 选择展示全屏
screen and a mute button both on
静音键既在屏幕上
the screen as well as within
又在 Touch bar
Touch Bar.
上
And you'll notice that the order
你会注意到这些键的
of these buttons match.
顺序是对应的
If I go ahead and change the
如果你将语言换成阿拉伯语
language to Arabic, you'll
你会发现
notice that the on-screen
屏幕上的按钮
buttons will actually reverse
键的顺序已经反转
their order.
过来了
And we do the same in Touch Bar
我们对 Touch Bar 也要
to maintain that matching order.
保持同样的对应顺序
But it's important to note that
但是需要注意
not everything actually flips.
不是所有东西都能反转
The escape key and the control
退出键和控制条
strip stay where they're at
要保持不动 无论是从左到右
whether it's left to right or
还是从右到左
right to left.
阅读
And only specific groups of
只有特殊的项组
items should possibly flip.
才有可能反转
Such as the center controls
比如中央控制器
here, which we're flipping to
我们可以反转以符合
match on-screen UI.
屏幕上的 UI
As well as the image and label
打进电话的图片
about the incoming call are
和标签也是可以
flipped.
反转的
But the position of that item
但是项的位置并没有
did not move to the opposite
移动到 Touch Bar 的
side of the Touch Bar.
另外一边
This is easy to achieve using
使用 10.13 里的 GroupTouchBarItem
GroupTouchBarItem's new group
的新用户组界面布局方向属性
user interface layout direction
可以很轻松的实现
property in 10.13.
这一点
You can simply set this to
你可以设置它去反映
reflect NSAppuserInterface
NSApp 用户界面
LayoutDirection.
布局方向
Now, I'm sure you're aware
现在 我相信你们意识到
languages aren't just left to
语言不只是从左到右或者
right or right to left, they
从右到左
also have variable length
它也有长度有变化的
strings.
字符串
And it's important to remember
这是你在设计
that when you're designing your
你的 UI 时要重点
UI.
记住的
In this example, I have a list
在这个例子里
of some of my favorite ocean
我有一个我最爱的海洋生物
animals.
的清单
And I ran this exact same app in
我用英文和德文运行
both English and in German.
同一个 App
In English I was able to fit 6
用英文时 我可以匹配
items here.
6 个项
But in German I only have 5.
用德文我只能匹配 5 个
That's because the shark item
这是因为鲨鱼项
actually didn't have enough room
没有足够的空间去
to fit in Touch Bar and so it
匹配 Touch Bar
was hidden from the user.
所以它在用户面前是隐藏的
Which is really unfortunate for
这对德文用户来说是
our German friends.
很不幸的
Now, you might be tempted to fix
现在 你可能试图用
this using constraints, tying
约束来解决这个问题
each button to be a specific
将每个键都设置为一样
width.
宽
But that's actually not a great
但是这不是一个好的解决办法
solution because as we change
因为在我们变换位置的时候
localizations, we're almost
我们基本上一定会
certainly going to cause
引起它们其中
clipping in one of them.
一个的反转
Now, GroupTouchBarItem actually
现在 事实上
has a great way of handling this
从 10.13 开始 GroupTouchBarItem 有一个
for you automatically starting
能自动处理这个问题
in 10.13.
的方法
And I encourage you to check out
我鼓励你们去参加
the "Advanced Touch Bar Talk"
今天晚些时候召开的叫做
later today which will do a dive
“Advanced Touch Bar（Touch Bar 进阶）”的演讲
into exactly what happens.
它将深入探讨到底是怎么做的
Now, we have a few bonus topics.
现在 我们有几个额外的话题
These are all covered great in
它们将包括在文档中
documentation, but we'll mention
但我还是要进行
them briefly now.
简要的介绍
First is the
首先要提到的是
ColorPickerTouchBarItem.
ColorPickerTouchBarItem
This allows users to interact
它让用户可以直接
with the color picker right
在 Touch Bar 上
through Touch Bar.
选择颜色
They can choose the exact color
他们可以选择他们
that they want.
想要的颜色
They can even change color
他们甚至可以改变颜色模型
models and your document can
并且你的文档可以对
restrict which color models are
颜色模型支持的
supported.
加以约束
Users also have access to their
用户也可以使用
favorite color swatches.
他们最爱的色板
So, it's a really great
这真的是很好的
experience.
体验
We also have a
我们还有分享服务
SharingServicePicker.
拾取器
This lets you easily share a
这将是你能通过邮件
document through mail, messages,
信息 AirDrop 甚至是
air drop, or even third-party
第三方保险的服务
insurance services.
共享文件
And these are all the same
这些都是通过同一个
services available through the
分享表完成的
share sheet.
服务
And finally, we have an
最后 我们有一个 NSScrubber
NSScrubber, which is actually a
它其实是一个视图
view, not an item.
而不是一个项
This could be the view of a
它可以是 Touch Bar 项的
Touch Bar item.
视图
And you can see in an
这就和我们刚才说到的
application such as calendar's
日历里的时间轴
timeline, Safari's tabs or even
Safari 的标签页
the color swatches of the color
色板里的
picker that we just talked
颜色选择器
about.
一样
It's a very versatile, very
这是一个多功能的
fluid control.
可变的控件
And it was designed specifically
它是特别为 Touch Bar
for Touch Bar.
设计的
You can find out more about this
你可以在之前的演讲中
at the advanced talk, which will
了解到更多更深的
do a deep dive on exactly how to
关于如何使用这个
use this control.
控件的内容
Now, we've covered a ton of
好了 我们今天已经讲到了
material today.
很多内容
We talked about the NSTouchBar
我们讲了 NSTouchBar API
API, how it's tied to the
它如何连接响应器链
responder chain, how you can use
你如何向用户提供
it to provide context-sensitive
上下文敏感
controls for your users.
的控件
We've talked about the
我们讲到 NSTouchBarItem
NSTouchBarItem and all of its
和所有 AppKit
subclasses that AppKit provides
提供的子类以及
and their unique functionality.
它们独一无二的功能
So, you now know enough to go
所以 今天你知道得足够多了
adopt Touch Bar in your
已经可以在你的应用程序中
applications today.
采用 Touch Bar 技术了
While you're there, you should
你在采用的时候
definitely enable user
你绝对应该让你的用户
customization so that users can
能够进行自定义
get the exact experience that
使你的用户得到他们
they're looking for.
想要的体验
And definitely remember to
一定记得在设计你的 UI 时
design you UI with localization
进行本地化 这样
in mind so that all users have a
你的用户才会获得
great experience.
好的体验
For more information, you can
要想了解更多信息
check out our developer website.
你可以登录我们的开发者网站
We have some related sessions
我们有一些你可能会
you might be interested in.
感兴趣的相关会议
"Choosing the Right Cocoa
“Choosing the Right Cocoa Container View
Container View" will look at
（选择正确的 Cocoa 视图容器）”
when you might want to choose a
可以解决当你想将堆栈视图
grid view over a stack view.
换成网格视图的问题
And this could be important
这很重要 因为你可以将
because you could use one of
这些视图容器中的一个
these container views as the
用作 TouchBarItem 的
content view of a TouchBarItem.
内容视图
We also have the "Advanced Touch
还有我们提到过很多次的
Bar Talk" which we mentioned
“Avanced Touch Bar（Touch Bar 进阶）”演讲
several times, which will do a
这个视频里介绍了
dive into extra functionality of
很多 Touch Bar 的
Touch Bar.
额外功能
Thank you all so much for
感谢大家
joining us today.
今天的到来
Enjoy the rest of your
请享受接下来
conference
的会议
[ Applause ]
[掌声]